all right guys
i promised to do a video about my
setup and methodology and process
for a long time now and it's the most
common question i get asked
to explain my process and method
and setup selection and uh
i promised to do a video for way too
long
and uh yeah so
enough is enough uh
it's time to actually do it instead of
promising things so
i have a few uh basic setups
that i trade over and over and over
again
let's start with the parabolic short
what is the parabolic short let's let's
take a few examples it's a stock that
gets
very extended in a short amount of time
so there's two components to it you have
a percentage move
preferably it's you know two three
hundred percent
or maybe even a thousand percent plus
in a short amount of time like three
days
five days uh two weeks or something
uh it's updated goes up
a lot in a short amount of time and
preferably it goes up
on nothing you know some speculation or
hype or just a pure pump
uh let's take ino for example recently
this thing
like this is what you're looking for
something that's just straight up
straight up with no dips this thing went
up 300 percent in one two
three four five sessions on the fifth
day
now this is important you have to wait
you can't short on the first or second
date generally
sometimes it's work it works shorting
stocks on the first or second day but i
prefer to wait the ones that
go up for three four even five days
those are the best ones
[Music]
uh because you you want to be in a
position of strength you don't want to
start shorting it down here because you
think it's a piece of pump
and it's up too much you don't want to
short it on day one or day two
okay and this is the trade i actually
did real time
in on the stream so those of you been
following my stream you
you remember this trade i know several
of you they traded with me
the fifth day it's a big euphoric gap
up and then it just tanks okay
let's look at the um now i don't have
the intraday
five minutes short available right
now i think nope i don't have the five
minute
chart where let's look at the 10 minute
chart
uh or maybe 15 minutes short yeah
let's see here okay so 15 minutes all
right still i need the five minute
but pretty much what you saw was it had
a little bit of push out of the gate
and then it took out opening range lows
now this is key
like i talk a lot about opening range
highs
and opening range lows
and i trade them all the time if i want
to short
opening range highs sorry opening range
lows is usually where i wanna short it
and the opening range can be the one
minute chart
like a one minute candle the first one
minute candle it can be that five minute
candle first five minute candle or it
could be the first
hourly candle like like this these
charts here
i use the one hour short a lot
uh and it can also be
like for example on ino the opening
range lows on the 60 minute chart was
1620 on this day here
but on the one minute chart it was up
here in the 18s and also in the five
minute chart it was also here in the
18th i really i don't have
the five minute and one-minute charts
right now on this platform
um i should have prepared better for
this stream it was kind of sporadic
i didn't really prepare but yeah
let's look at an uh look at the recent
example
um mrna
this one wasn't an opening range lows
play it was more of a
it was still a range break like i also
talk a lot about
long uh tight ranges
so mrna was another candidate it's been
up
500 percent it's it's a large cap stock
in six months for a large cap stock
that's a big move
that's a very big move a lot of hype and
speculation with their
uh vaccine kovi 19 vaccine etc etc
uh
and they had kind of
decent data on this day here the stock
was already extended
they uh
released some decent data but it was
only from eight patients which is kind
of irrelevant
so this one i was stalking for a good
risk watch set up
now it did have i i think i even shorted
it i don't remember if i did i
i think i shorted on the opening range
lows and took a loss on it
this is like last week i really don't
remember i'm so bad at remembering
trades
but i may have taken a loss on the first
trip and in late day
just went in a tight tight range and
late date started fading and that's
that's where you got a tight tight range
on it
two dollars raised two dollars to make
potentially 20 25 on a downside that's
exactly what happened just
straight down from there so this was
another extended stock
uh but it wasn't up like three four days
in a row it was yeah it had just been
flagging for a week and then it gapped
up a date on this uh
on this news but it was already pretty
overextended so
it's kinda similar setup to
the ino setup i was talking about
but it wasn't straight up as violently
as this ino but the key in both of these
you don't
randomly short them you wait for them to
actually
start going lower you don't stop uh
you know start randomly picking tops you
wait for weakness
so that's why you wait for this opening
range lows
or uh mid late day fades
so it's kind of the same trade but that
variation
of of the same trade pretty much and ino
had a exactly
similar setup a little bit later in
april
also it went up 100
in just five six sessions and then you
had this a little bit of a peak day
you you pretty much count the days you
know it's up one two
three four even on this steven even if
it
the candle here is red the stock was
still higher on this day
the candle here is red because it closed
lower than it opened but it still closed
higher than the previous day so it was
still an update
so how what one two three four five six
on the seventh day
you get this uh little bit of a reversal
but it actually was a pretty big
reversal
where are we
i can't find it on the five minutes or
oh okay i have to look at a 10 minute
chart
and it's the same thing exactly
same thing opening range lows was the
key
now in the 10 minute shot the opening
range lows is here 15
17 or so but i think on the one and
five-minute
uh charts it was higher like mid or high
15s
so you wait for that opening range lows
because the stock has been straight up
then it triggers it tried to bounce and
i'm gonna
introduce you another concept the vivap
this is an
indicator i use a lot when shorting only
when i'm shorting stocks pretty much
or when i play me in a version trade
sometimes i do use it on the long side
too but
only when i like do bounce plays i'm
gonna go through that later
so it tests viva can't get above
it holds below viva midday
similar to what mrna did it built a uh
range for several hours and then it
breaks below that
and then it just you know fade straight
down then it went sideways a little bit
for a few days and then it had another
leg lower
uh and i should also mention i'm mostly
a swing trader i don't
do trades for day trades when i do a
trade i do it to hold for several days
or weeks if i'm short and
generally for weeks and months if i go
long
so let's look at some mean aversion long
trades
um i'm gonna see
one that i remember i had a really good
trade on
was on gbtc this is a bitcoin etf
back in december 2017.
now you should already already recognize
this setup here
you have something that's up hundreds
and hundreds of percent
in in a short amount of time you know
has a leg higher it goes sideways as a
leg higher goes sideways another leg
higher then it goes up
a bunch of days in a row it pretty much
doubles
in in a week and then you had this
blow-off day and
i don't have the intraday shot for it
right now but
it was a similar shot to what i showed
on mrna and
i know you get
vivap fails and then it just starts
fading and you have this you have a set
risk reward
uh but i'm gonna talk about this bounce
now this is uh
similar to the short set up the median
version of parabolic short this is the
parabolic loan
the same concept you have a stock that's
down 40 50
60 percent in in this uh case it's down
almost
70 percent in one two three four
sessions
the fourth day gaps down big has a
washout a little bit of a washout goes a
little bit lower from the open
and that's the same thing it starts it
reclaims v-map
it holds above viva puts in opening
range lows
and that's when you go long when it once
it starts proving
itself and it bounced the total move
higher was
110 110 in two days
actually you know what i'm gonna look at
i'm gonna find the intraday short for
you
um let's see here
uh okay let's see
gbtc i'm gonna find the introduce short
i'm gonna
find the shot for both the short and the
long this was such a perfect trade you
want to find these
stocks with big big ranges that's where
the big money is
let's see here so i'm gonna show you
guys
okay
19. so i'm going to show you this is
evernote i have a
huge database of shards and stocks that
i've been building for years and years
this is how you build an a
edge so chibi dc was actually a little
bit shopping now i'm
gonna show you guys on this this day
here when it peaked
and when it started the big decline okay
so it was a little bit choppy intraday
it was weak at first it gapped down but
then it went straight up
reclaimed vivap i don't have evap on
this short
but uh it reclaimed evap
actually took out the previous day size
and then midday it peaked
it started uh it went below viva app
retested viva app and then it started
fading
and that's when you have a set risk
reward because you know
a lot of stocks they start fading in mid
late day especially these momentum
stocks
and that's where you have a set risk you
would you know you don't have to guess
where the top is gonna be
and then it faded seventy percent almost
in four or five days
and now this day here this is the five
minute chart okay
uh so this day here is the day it
bounced
this is that day
so it's it's like you switch this uh
like
you flip the short right it's the same
trade but on the long side
it's extended to the downside and it
starts putting in
it puts in the first green candle like
this is also something i talked about
the first green and the first red
candle like if you have something that's
going straight up or straight down
uh you wait for the first like let's say
in this case
it's something that gets three that's
getting really overextended on the
downside you wait for the first screen
five minute candle
okay before you buy then you can use
that lower that candle
as a stop so in this case you get the
first screen candle and this is a trade
i traded
i i did trade but i didn't stream at
this time this is like a year before i
started streaming
uh so you add a little bit then it takes
out the opening range highs that's where
you add more and go straight up
unfortunately i sold this thing way
early i don't think even i hold it
held it overnight and then the next
state went up another 20 30 percent
so these are the mean aversion traits
the parabolic short
and the parabolic longs i'm just gonna
do a quick overview i'm not gonna go
into details there are many nuances to
these traits but these are like
uh you know the most important concepts
of these trades then another uh
important setup i use are the breakouts
and the earnings gapping gap versus
earnings breakouts i'm going to show you
some
examples of
ones i have traded
recently uh this delicious t-doc i
traded this on the stream
they had good earnings report they beat
both the eps revenue they got it higher
and the stock gaps up and goes up on big
volume
okay it takes out a long range a
multi-year range
i'm going to show you guys the short on
the
weekly chart um i'm going to show you
the weekly chart
so this is where it broke out on high
volume
you have a stock that's been building
higher lows for over a year
took out the range this is a growth
stock they're in the right sector
right business things are going well
this is where the stock is up
straight up since 2016. things are going
well for them
and then a gap up on a good earnings
report this is what started the big move
unfortunate you know hop went up 160
percent in a few months
unfortunately i sold this thing i think
in the like
105 or something i don't remember
exactly i sold it way too early
it doubled after i sold it pretty much
another example would be the xcm this is
another
one i traded very similar short
you wait for a long range break it needs
to gap up on good earnings speed
analyst estimates uh have good growth
numbers
uh it the eps
grew by 261 percent year over year
and the revenue grew by 49 this is a
growth stock the estimates
for the next year were 156 percent
or the same year this is 2019 and the
estimates for the next year which is
2020 was 54
so they were going to keep growing
and it went straight up now they don't
all go straight up obviously i'm gonna
i'm just showing perfect examples
obviously to take a lot of losses
in fact about 60 percent of my trades
are losses
um even more i think
i think even 70 percent i think last
year my
70 almost 70 percent my trades were
losses or breakevens
and yet i'm wildly profitable and that's
because you have to have small losers
big winners
anyways dxcm this is the weekly short
similar setup you have a higher lows for
six months you have a range
like a year-long range then it gaps up
on good earnings
beats analyst estimates guides higher
etc etc things are going well for this
company
and it more than doubles it had a big
shakeout here during the corona crisis
where it bounced
perfectly off the rising 200 day
um so i'm going to show you some
examples
from my own portfolio of these setups
let's look at mrna like mrna i went over
i'm still short this thing i'm still
short from this stay
here now i've been adding on the 60
minute ranges for example yesterday
it gapped down while the market was
gapping up
it showed relative weakness this is also
a concept i talked a lot about
relative strength and relative weakness
if you're stalking a short stop for a
short and it starts showing relative
weakness that's a good sign and vice
versa for if you're stocking something
on the long side
so an opening range lows here i added to
it
yesterday and went straight down and
it's gapping down today
while the markets are gapping higher
spies are up like
almost one percent overnight oh more
more
1.3 so mrna
ibio this is a stock i've been long for
a while
um this is also like a range break this
is like a small tiny piece of stock
i'm long because it's a theme stock
uh like kobe 19 is right now the theme
the kobe 19 vaccines are very hot theme
right now
so technically what did i see i saw a
range break several months this is a
former momentum stock i had a big move
back in february
on corona this is a corona related pump
and then here had a big volume day
or not that big but you know above
average volume so i thought hey
why not it's a good risk award why can't
this thing double
a lot of these things are doubling w uh
this one
is a range break from yesterday
i shorted it this thing is up it was up
840 percent in like a few months
so very overextended name this is just a
variation of the same
setup you wait for weakness on a very
strong stock
and yesterday lost the rising 20 day for
the first time since this
whole big move and today it's gapping
lower even though the
markets are gapping higher so it's
showing relative weakness
i think next stop for this thing would
be maybe 130
120 area livongo this is an earnings
related trade
it's a recent ipo i bought it a couple
of months ago
had a multi-month like six months
sideways move
recent ipo they sold it off
you know it went straight down from the
ipo it was you know kind of
expensive stock and the market wasn't
sure
if they could sustain the growth etc etc
but then it
you know guided higher
stock gapped up on higher on volume if
that didn't have big volume but i i did
a small position because it just looked
really good
ipo breakout the ipo breakouts can be
super powerful and it's
straight up since and i'm still holding
about half of my shares
fastly another one i bought like a
couple of weeks ago another ipo
breakout this thing has pretty much gone
sideways since the ipo
and then suddenly they had a good report
38 no no no profits but 38 revenue
growth good guidance
etc big big volume by far the biggest
volume then you
it traded like in the first five minutes
you saw the big volume coming in it
traded
average daily volume which is about one
and a half million shares in like the
first
i don't know five or so minutes 10
minutes
so it was fairly you know pretty it was
obvious pretty early it was gonna be a
high volume day
so i bought it and uh yeah i'm gonna
show the p
l on everything later i'm gonna show you
my portfolio
at the end of the video on all of these
stocks i'm in right now these longs and
shorts
and vacs another one i've been talking
about i did short it this day here
another one of these over extended names
up fourteen hundred percent in a few
months and then he had
the first states just you know getting
extended first day
it showed some weakness took out opening
range lows
started testing vivap failed at viva app
and that's where i shorted it this is
the 60 minute chart i shorted it here at
56 saturday i remember
correctly melee and other earnings play
i'm long
same concept you know big long range
break
year long range break and uh big volume
big volume on the earnings day earning
speed
uh guides higher et cetera et cetera
arctic is a small
just a small hype kobe 19 vaccine play
i bought it here and inside of this flag
when when it was obvious it was building
higher lows i think i bought it here
40 low 45s
this is another type of setup like high
tide flags
pdd also another high tide flag i bought
here
it's a china growth stock very good
earnings numbers
um i didn't buy it on the earnings
report but i did buy it when it
bounced off the rising 20 day after
coming out of a long range
and had a clean breakout here and it's
straight up since
shag now obviously all of these trades
are profitable
because i sell my losers i keep my
winners
and it's a concept i talk about a lot
small winners big
sorry small losses small losers big
winners
okay that's why i i i can be widely
profitable with
while being wrong seventy percent for
the time shake another one another
earnings breakout
which sold you know over a long
year-long pace
etc it's the same concept sc
uh same concept here uh had a flag
uh where did i buy it yeah i did buy it
here on this day here
came out held up very well uh during the
corona
crisis flagged and it broke out of this
little flag and it was
it's it's like one of the fastest
growing stocks in the market right now
you want to be
in the growth stocks the ones that
have bright futures
you don't want to be in something that's
you know as negative earnings or
or very slow earnings revenue growth you
want the stocks growing
30 50 100
fmcid it's just a pump play
i'm not even gonna talk about it it's
just a thin piece of one this is
another one
uh it's a kobe 19 related name
um it's a thin name i bought it on the
flag break here had good earnings
they sell some kind of uh respiratory
devices to hospitals which is
you know something that's a very hot
product right now with the corona
emph i'm short this is an example of an
overextended trade
straight up we had one leg up second leg
up
third fourth and fifth leg up on the
third day
opening range lows that's where i
shorted it
or i need short opening range though i
showed it here midday
with a 60 minute chart you can clearly
see
you have a multi-hour range and then you
have this breakdown of this range
so you have a tight tight range here you
can
your risk is like a dollar
and i still i'm still short like half
size just trailing it pen
another example one i did on the stream
yesterday
i'm gonna show the intraday chart you
had the opening range lows it failed
that view app not
once but twice
and i i showed it opening range flows
and i was thinking about adding it when
it add a
failed viva another time midday uh but i
never did
uh vt iq a perfect example of amino
version short
i unfortunately took a 125 000
loss on it i was a little bit too
aggressive too early and then i
didn't add back when it showed some
weakness and
yeah it worked out well it went down
over 30 40
and then i played the bounce i'm still
along it i i bought the bounce on this
day here
the 60 minute chart took out a little
bit of a range but it's just a variation
it wasn't like a super clean setup it's
a variation of
the bounce setup uh bldp breakout
momentum stock it's in the right sector
fuel cells fuels there's a super height
right now
uh and it had a bull flag tie type bull
flag and it gaps up on big volume
and that's you know where i bought it i
bought opening range highs 1040s or
1050s i think
mark this is a pump stock um
but it's the same concept you have a
flag and you buy it fas
had a breakout yesterday it's a triple
financial etf
it's been pretty much flagging off the
lows
building a tight tight range over the
past week and then it
capped up on high volume and opening
range size was the entry
i actually took a loss on it first
because it
i bought it here near the open
and then it faded it actually didn't
take out the lows of the day but
i had to stop a little bit higher i
could stop that and then i re-bought it
when it took out the opening range highs
a little bit later and it's straight up
since the markets are gapping up a lot
and clh the same thing here
it's also again it's a variation of the
same setup
you have a range break breakout
i'm not gonna talk about it much it's
just a c cell the same thing um
a range break set up on a momentum stock
like these things are super beaten down
they have a lot of range the key is to
trade stocks with
range i see a lot of people they trade
stocks they have no volume there's no
range the middle of a range there's
nothing going on
and they're getting super excited about
their stocks and i'm like
no just know trade stocks that have
volume and range
that's where the money is all right i'm
gonna show you guys
my p l and this is why i focus on
swing trading and update trading because
the big money is in swing trading this
is my portfolio screenshot taken about
15 minutes ago
since i'm at swedish time the market
opens in 35 minutes
nine nine third it's sorry 8 56
u.s eastern time and the market opens
9 30 eastern time so it's in 34 minutes
uh you know some of these positions i've
had for months
livongo i talked about this one this is
my oldest position sc is
my also very old position
uh and this is how my portfolio looks
like right now
i i sold a bunch of stuff pre-market i
sold some pldp
this we have a big gap up and i just
wanna light i'm heavily heavily long
right now
i'm short a bunch of stuff but i just
wanted to you know look into
this euphoric little open here we're
having
uh some nclh so some
uh covered some mrna because like i
talked about earlier in the video mrna
is showing relative weakness
it's gapping down well the markets are
gapping up so it's
locking into weakness i'm always looking
my lungs into
strength and my shorts into weakness and
then i train my stops
uh and i also sold some fas
and i'm probably gonna get rid of more
stuff and the reason why
everything is green in my portfolio is
again i
sell my losers okay you get rid of your
losers
you keep your winners and i've been
building this portfolio over the past
six weeks or so my oldest position is
levongo
like i was all cash at one point during
the corona crash
and then in vongo let's see i bought it
7th of april so about
about seven weeks or so this were
the time i've been building my portfolio
all right
i hope you got value oh no never mind i
actually have more things to go through
uh never mind uh quick
about my scans uh i scan for stocks that
go up a lot
uh like i have this watch list today
today's momentum watch list this watch
list 271 names
i get these stocks from these scans
so that's what that's my nightly scans
right
so i scan for stocks that trade 60
million dollar volume
60 million dollars in daily
volume average daily range is the
percentage range
during a day that has to be at least 2.4
percent
and it has to be among the seven percent
or so
strongest stocks if i do this scan right
now i get four items i don't know why i
only get four items there should be more
i think there's something wrong right
now with tc2 thousand
there should be like 40 names let's do
the one month scan again 60 million
dollar volume
average daily range past 20 days 2.4
percent and among the seven percenters
of strongest stocks
and i only get four always because i'm
including pre-market data i'm shutting
off the pre-market data i'm gonna
okay let's see now okay now it's yeah 47
stocks okay
all right so i have these for different
time frames one and a half year one
month one year six months three months
blah blah blah
etc then i also scan for
five day gainers 60 million dollar
volume up
25 at least past five days so i'm
pretty much scanning for stocks that are
strong because that
among the strong stocks that's where you
get the best shorts
and the best longs then i also scam for
losers
you know stocks that are down a lot the
past one or two years
then i have a some intraday scans it's
the same thing pretty much
scanning for stocks that are strong
then i also have watch list with the
best and strongest
growth stocks strongest are my
the best or the best this fastest
growing and the best momentum stocks
then i have
strong strong air
and strong so these stocks these get
these ones i also go through every every
day every night
and also scan them intraday like this is
very big
among these stocks is where the big
money is made right now there's a lot of
software technology stocks in there
but depending on you know year and
market cycle you can get a lot of like
commodity related stocks or cyclicals
you can get a lot of biotech related
right now we're in a market cycle where
technology and software
are dominant those are the fastest
sectors and have the best momentum so
most of these stocks in those watch
lists are technology and software
all right this is uh pretty much
pretty much it and then i compile a
watch list
every night look through my scans
and start stalking stuff
and it's always nice if the stocks you
want to go long showing
relative strength and the stocks you
want to go short are showing relative
weakness
um all right
um i think this is a good starter video
maybe i'll do a longer more detailed
video later
this is a very unprepared video um
and i hope you got the value from it
this you know if you learn these
concepts
you can make millions you can make
millions per year for the rest of your
life
but you really need to do your own you
know do your own
research i've done my i've done my
research like i've
i've studied thousands tens of thousands
of stocks look at this this is my
evernote database
like i have breakouts from 1980
right i have like
tens of thousands of uh stocks here
these are just breakouts
you have to train your brain to
recognize
not only the stock patterns but also the
news and how they
move relation to each other and the
market
these are like earning scampers
let's look at saunders this is like 2005
i think
capped up on big volume 2005
and then it went up over a couple of
hundred percent in like six months
uh anyway you gotta do this work
yourself
no one no one can help you with this
like
this is how you build build mastery
instead of following people and uh
begging for stock tips and just unfollow
these stupid day traders that are
you know pumping stocks on twitter
or you know having some paid chat room
where they
tell you what to buy what to sell
they're not help they're not your
friends they're not helping you you need
to do the research yourself
i have a free stream where you can ask
questions where i gave trading give
trading ideas
it's not entertainment i'm not selling
anything i'm doing my own trading
i i'm quiet most of the time since i'm
busy trading
but when i get a few minutes over free
time i ask
i answer questions and
i provide feedback to those who
want it all right i hope you got some
value out of this video
and take care